American Psychosomatic Society Records Finding Aid
Oskar Diethelm Library
- Governance
  - Council, 1943 - 1986
    - Committees, 1943 - 1958; Arranged chronologically. Includes the minutes, slates, ballots, and administrative correspondence of the Nominating Committee of the Council, the body responsible for nominating Council members.
      - Nominating Committee, 1952 - 1953 (Box 157)
      - Nominating Committee, 1953 - 1954 (Box 157)
      - Nominating Committee, 1954 - 1955 (Box 157)
      - Nominating Committee, 1955 - 1956 (Box 157)
      - Nominating Committee, 1956 - 1957 (Box 157)
      - Nominating Committee, 1957 - 1958 (Box 157)
      - Nominating Committee, 1958 - 1959 (Box 158)
      - Nominating Committee, 1959 - 1960 (Box 158)
      - Nominating Committee, 1960 - 1961 (Box 158)
      - Nominating Committee, 1961 - 1962 (Box 158)
      - Nominating Committee, 1962 - 1963 (Box 158)
      - Nominating Committee, 1963 - 1964 (Box 158)
      - Nominating Committee, 1964 - 1965 (Box 158)
      - Nominating Committee, 1965 - 1966 (Box 158)
      - Nominating Committee, 1966 - 1967 (Box 158)
      - Nominating Committee, 1967 - 1968 (Box 158)
      - Nominating Committee, 1968 - 1969 (Box 158)
      - Nominating Committee, 1969 - 1970 (Box 158)
      - Nominating Committee, 1971 (Box 158)
      - Nominating Committee, 1972 (Box 158)
      - Nominating Committee, 1973 (Box 158)
      - Nominating Committee, 1974 (Box 159)
      - Nominating Committee, 1975 (Box 159)
      - Nominating Committee, 1976 (Box 159)
      - Nominating Committee, 1977 (Box 159)
      - Nominating Committee, 1978 (Box 159)
      - Nominating Committee, 1979 (Box 159)
      - Nominating Committee, 1980 (Box 159)
      - Nominating Committee, 1981 (Box 159)
      - Nominating Committee, 1982 (Box 159)
      - Nominating Committee, 1983 (Box 159)
    - Special Issues, 1955 - 1956; File includes correspondence reflecting the Council's decision against expelling from its membership a Dr. Ethan Allan Brown, following statements by a Dr. Kaufman attacking the legitimacy of Dr. Brown's "M.D." qualifications.
      - "Kaufman-Brown" matter (re. charges by Dr. Kaufman against the legitimacy of Dr. Brown's "M.D." qualifications), 1955 - 1956 (Box 159)
  - Officers, 1944 - 1971
    - Presidents, 1944 - 1971; Arranged alphabetically by name of officer. Presidents served terms of one year, with exceptions to this rule falling during the years soon after the Society's founding. Files in this series probably were kept by presidents themselves. Consequently, materials in this subgroup may also be found in other portions of the collections. Included here are general correspondence, annual reports, conference schedules and agendas, presidential addresses, membership rosters, membership dues reports and eligibility rules, material on compulsory health care (1948-1949) and committee selection, committee minutes, and information related to publication of journal articles. Material in Dr. William Greene's files include background information about the history of the Society.
      - Alexander, Franz, 1947 - 1948 (Box 160)
      - Binger, Carl, 1963 - 1964 (Box 160)
      - Cleghorn, Robert, 1965 - 1966; 2 folders (Box 160)
      - Cobb, Stanley, 1955 - 1956; 2 folders (Box 160)
      - Engel, George, 1953 - 1954 (Box 160)
      - Ferris, Eugene, 1949 - 1950 (Box 160)
      - Greene, William, 1967 - 1968 (Box 160)
      - Greene, William, 1968 (Box 160)
      - Background material on history of the Society, Undated (Box 160)
      - Grinker, Roy, 1951 - 1952 (Box 160)
      - Hinkle, Lawrence, 1966 - 1967 (Box 160)
      - Holmes, Thomas, 1968 - 1969 (Box 160)
      - Hoskins, Roy, 1944 - 1946 (Box 160)
      - Kubie, Lawrence, 1954 - 1955 (Box 160)
      - Litz, Theodore, 1957 - 1958 (Box 160)
      - Margolin, Sydney, 1952 - 1953; 2 folders (Box 160)
      - Mason, John, 1969 - 1970 (Box 160)
      - Meyer, Eugene, 1964 - 1965 (Box 160)
      - Mirsky, Arthur, I., 1956 - 1957 (Box 160)
      - Reiser, Morton, 1960 - 1961 (Box 160)
      - Richmond, Julius, 1962 - 1963 (Box 160)
      - Rosenbaum, Milton, 1958 - 1959 (Box 161)
      - Saul, Leon, 1948 - 1949; 2 folders (Box 161)
      - Senn, Milton, 1950 - 1951 (Box 161)
      - Weiner, Herbert, 1971 - 1972; 3 folders (Box 161)
      - Weiss, Edward, 1946 - 1948; 3 folders (Box 161)
      - Wittkower, Eric, 1959 - 1962; 3 folders (Box 161)
      - Wolf, Stewart, 1961 - 1962 (Box 161)
    - Secretary-Treasurers, 1944 - 1971; Arranged alphabetically by name of officer. Secretary-Treasurers served the Society for terms of three years, though exceptions to this rule are found during the early years of the Society. Included in these files are general correspondence, some annual business meeting minutes, and a variety of reports.
      - Binger, Carl, 1947 (Box 161)
      - Greene, William, 1963 - 1966; 3 folders (Box 161)
      - Lidz, Theodore, 1953 - 1956; 4 folders (Box 162)
      - Margolin, Sydney, 1951; 3 folders (Box 162)
      - Meyer, Eugene, 1959 - 1963; 5 folders (Box 162)
      - Redlich, Fritz, 1951 - 1953; 3 folders (Box 163)
      - Reiser, Morton, 1956 - 1959; 4 folders (Box 163)
      - Weiner, Herbert, 1966 - 1970; 3 folders (Box 163)
- Research Activities
  - Committees, 1942 - 1951
    - Correspondence and Minutes, 1942 - 1951; Arranged alphabetically by committee title. Includes administrative correspondence and minutes of the various Research Committees. Most correspondence reflects the planning, scheduling, and selection of topics for discussion at committee meetings. Research committees were formed in 1942 to supervise the specific research program of each of the several disciplines participating in the new field of psychosomatic medicine. They were dissolved in the late 1940s. Soon after, a system of geographically based discussion "Forums" was organized in their place. A list of Research Committee names and members as of 1946 is located in the 1946 Bulletin. SEE: Record Group 7, Box 1.
      - Committee on Cardiovascular Disease, 1943 - 1947; 3 folders (Box 164)
      - Committee on Cutaneous and Allied Diseases, Tuberculosis in Children Project, 1945 - 1946 (Box 164)
      - Committee on Cutaneous and Allied Diseases, 1943 - 1946; 4 folders (Box 164)
      - Committee on Cutaneous and Allied Diseases, Psychosomatic Aspects of Tuberculosis, 1943 - 1946 (Box 164)
      - Committee on Diabetes Project, 1946 (Box 164)
      - Committee on Education, 1943 - 1944 (Box 164)
      - Committee on Fatigue, 1942; 2 folders (Box 164)
      - Committee on Gastroenterological, 1943 - 1947 (Box 164)
      - Committee on Industrial Health, 1943 - 1946; 3 folders (Box 164)
      - Committee on Infancy and Early Childhood, 1943 - 1944; 4 folders (Box 165)
      - Committee on Infancy and Early Childhood, 1944 - 1946; 4 folders (Box 165)
      - Committee on Medical Education and Fellowships, 1943 - 1944; 3 folders (Box 165)
      - Committee on Medical Education and Fellowships, 1945 - 1947; 3 folders (Box 165, Box 166)
      - Committee on Ob-G Project, 1943 - 1946; 4 folders (Box 166)
      - Committee on Psychosomatic Implications on Pain, 1943 (Box 166)
      - Committee on Physical Fitness, 1944 (Box 166)
      - Committee on Psychological Mechanism and Animal Experimentation, 1944; 3 folders (Box 166)
      - Committee on Psychological Mechanism and Animal Experimentation, 1945 - 1946; 3 folders (Box 166)
      - Committee on Psychological Methods and Concepts, 1944 - 1946; 3 folders (Box 167)
      - Committee on Psychosomatic Factors in Health Insurance, 1943 - 1946 (Box 167)
      - Committee on Psychosomatic Research, 1946 - 1947; 3 folders (Box 167)
      - Committee on Psychosomatic Research, 1943 - 1945; 2 folders (Box 167)
      - Committee on Psychosomatic Problems in Medical Education, Answers to Questionnaires, 1944; 2 folders (Box 167)
      - Committee on Psychosomatic Problems in Medical Education, 1944 (Box 168)
      - Committee on Public Education, 1943 - 1946 (Box 168)
      - Committee on Research Coordination, Answers to Questionnaires, 1948; 4 folders (Box 168)
      - Committee on Research Coordination, 1947 - 1951; 2 folders (Box 168)
      - Committee on Social and Cultural Problems, 1942 - 1946 (Box 168)
      - Committee on Social Work, 1943 - 1946 (Box 168)
      - Committee on War Medicine, 1943 - 1946 (Box 169)
      - American Public Health Convention, 1944; 2 folders (Box 169)
      - Joint Meeting with American Psychiatric Association, 1944 (Box 169)
      - Psychosomatic Library and Book Company, 1946 (Box 169)
    - Conference Proceedings, 1942 - 1951; Organized by Research Committee title. Some proceedings are accompanied by correspondence. Conference proceedings, typed transcripts of panel discussions and presentations held at each session of a research committee conference, include table of contents which list names of individual speakers. Transcripts of proceedings of the Society's annual meetings (1940s only) are located by year in Record Group 2 - Annual Meetings, in the Administrative Files subgroup, and proceedings of the 1945 regional meeting, held in place of the annual meeting cancelled because of the War, are found here as well. Some materials have sustained water damage and must be handled carefully.
      - Open Meeting on Psychosomatic Implications of Pain, 1943 (Box 170)
      - Conference of the Committee on Cardiovascular Disease, 1944 (Box 170)
      - Conference of the Committee on Infancy and Early Childhood, 1944 (Box 170)
      - Conference of the Committee on Cutaneous and Allied Diseases, 1944; 2 folders (Box 170)
      - Conference of the Committee on Physiological Mechanisms and Animal Experimentation, 1944; 2 folders (Box 170)
      - Conference of the Committee on Cutaneous and Allied Diseases, 1946; 2 folders (Box 170)
      - "Psychosomatic Medicine - The Relation of Mental Illness to Bodily Ill Health" at the New York Academy of Medicine, 1947 (Box 170)
      - Proceedings of the Military Session in Detroit, 1943 (Box 170)
  - Forums, 1949 - 1960; Organized by geographic location. After the Society dissolved its research committees, it began to encourage professionals (members and non-members of the Society) to meet together at forums held in various regions of the country. This subgroup contains correspondence reflecting planning and scheduling, attendance, and the selection of topics and speakers. Almost half of the correspondence documents forums held in New York City. The Society's forum program is described in a 1959 letter by Dr. Eugene Meyer.
    - Forum Los Angeles, CA, Undated (Box 171)
    - Forum San Francisco, CA, Undated (Box 171)
    - Forum Montreal, Canada, Undated (Box 171)
    - Forum Denver, CO, Undated (Box 171)
    - Forum New Haven, CT, Undated (Box 171)
    - Forum Washington, D.C., Undated (Box 171)
    - Forum Florida, Undated (Box 171)
    - Forum Chicago, IL, Undated (Box 171)
    - Forum Indianapolis, IN, Undated (Box 171)
    - Forum South Bend, IN, Undated (Box 171)
    - Forum Louisville, KY, Undated (Box 171)
    - Forum New Orleans, LA, Undated (Box 171)
    - Forum Maryland, Undated (Box 171)
    - Forum Boston, MA, Undated (Box 171)
    - Forum Detroit, MI, Undated (Box 171)
    - Forum Minneapolis, MN, Undated (Box 171)
    - Forum Rochester, MN, Undated (Box 171)
    - Forum St. Louis, MO, Undated (Box 171)
    - Forum Albany, NY, Undated (Box 171)
    - Forum Buffalo, NY, Undated (Box 171)
    - Forum New York City, 1949 - 1950 (Box 171)
    - Forum New York City, 1950 - 1951 (Box 171)
    - Forum New York City, 1951 - 1952 (Box 171)
    - Forum New York City, 1952 - 1953 (Box 171)
    - Forum New York City, 1953 - 1954 (Box 172)
    - Forum New York City, 1954 - 1955 (Box 172)
    - Forum New York City, 1955 - 1957; 2 folders (Box 172)
    - Forum New York City, 1958 (Box 172)
    - Forum New York City, 1959; 2 folders (Box 172)
    - Forum New York City, 1960 (Box 172)
    - Forum Rochester, NY, Undated (Box 172)
    - Forum Syracuse, NY, Undated (Box 172)
    - Forum Chapel Hill, NC, Undated (Box 172)
    - Forum Cincinnati, OH, Undated (Box 172)
    - Forum Cleveland, OH, Undated (Box 172)
    - Forum Oklahoma City, OK, Undated (Box 172)
    - Forum Portland, OR, Undated (Box 172)
    - Forum Philadelphia, PA, Undated (Box 172)
    - Forum Pittsburgh, PA, Undated (Box 172)
    - Forum Nashville, TN, Undated (Box 172)
    - Forum Houston, TX, Undated (Box 172)
    - Forum Alexandria, VA, Undated (Box 172)
    - Forum Charlottesville, VA, Undated (Box 172)
    - Forum Seattle, WA Preliminary Material, Undated (Box 172)
    - Dr. Mittleman, Chairman of Forum Program, 1949 - 1951 (Box 172)
    - Dr. Mittleman, Chairman on Committee on Psychosomatic Forums, 1951 - 1959 (Box 172)
  - Proposed Projects, 1945 - 1946; Files include correspondence and abstracted research proposals submitted to Council for funding consideration. Includes a proposal by Dr. Jacob Arlow regarding adolescent diabetes research (1945) and another by Dr. Jules Masserman on the topic of alcoholism (1946).
    - Dr. Jacob Arlow (adolescent diabetes research), 1945 (Box 172)
    - Dr. Jules Masserman (alcoholism research), 1946 (Box 172)
    - Miscellaneous (Dr. Bela Mittlemann, Dr. Harold Raoul Wainerdi Busm III, Dr. H.G. Wolff), 1945 - 1946 (Box 172)
- Membership
  - Administrative Files, 1947 - 1985; Arranged alphabetically by correspondent's last name. Includes information requests on a variety of topics (e.g. membership, publications, meetings) by members and others, membership lists (1948-1986 with gaps), a membership resignation list (1950-1951), a treasurer's report containing membership resignations and other information (1952), and a membership roster (1963).
    - Secretary Treasurer's report on membership, 1952 (Box 173)
    - Membership Roster, 1963 (Box 173)
    - B's, 1947 - 1985; 6 folders (Box 173)
    - C's, 1947 - 1985; 3 folders (Box 173)
    - D's, 1947 - 1985; 3 folders (Box 173)
    - E's, 1947 - 1985 (Box 174)
    - F's, 1947 - 1985; 3 folders (Box 174)
    - G's, 1947 - 1985; 5 folders (Box 174)
    - H's, 1947 - 1985; 3 folders (Box 174, Box 175)
    - I's, 1947 - 1985 (Box 175)
    - J's, 1947 - 1985; 2 folders (Box 175)
    - K's, 1947 - 1985; 4 folders (Box 175)
    - L's, 1947 - 1985; 3 folders (Box 175)
    - M's, 1947 - 1985; 5 folders (Box 175, Box 176)
    - N's, 1947 - 1985; 2 folders (Box 176)
    - O's, 1947 - 1985 (Box 176)
    - P's, 1947 - 1985; 3 folders (Box 176)
    - R's, 1947 - 1985; 3 folders (Box 176)
    - S's, 1947 - 1985; 6 folders (Box 177)
    - T's, 1947 - 1985; 2 folders (Box 177)
    - U's, 1947 - 1985 (Box 177)
    - V's, 1947 - 1985 (Box 177)
    - W's, 1947 - 1985; 3 folders (Box 177)
    - X's - Z's, 1947 - 1985 (Box 177)
    - Membership Lists, 1947 - 1985 (Box 177)
    - Membership Resignation List, 1948 - 1986 (Box 177)
  - Application Materials, 1941 - 1982; Both series have been arranged alphabetically by applicant's last name. Materials include handwritten or typed applications, correspondence regarding membership between members and applicants, and recommendations for or against membership by professionals. Applications include date and place of birth, education, occupational history, and publication lists (but not actual publications). The Past Members series includes application materials for deceased members and those who have terminated membership. The applications of the first members of the Society, including of editors and council members, are included here. The Rejected Applicants series includes some argumentative correspondence from applicants not accepted for membership.
    - Past Members, 1941 - 1982
      - A's, 1941 - 1982; 7 folders (Box 178)
      - B's, 1941 - 1982; 19 folders (Box 178, Box 179, Box 180)
      - C's, 1941 - 1982; 10 folders (Box 180, Box 181)
      - D's, 1941 - 1982; 8 folders (Box 182)
      - E's, 1941 - 1982; 4 folders (Box 183)
      - F's, 1941 - 1982; 11 folders (Box 183, Box 184)
      - G's, 1941 - 1982; 10 folders (Box 184, Box 185)
      - H's, 1941 - 1982; 11 folders (Box 186, Box 187)
      - I's, 1941 - 1982 (Box 187)
      - J's, 1941 - 1982; 3 folders (Box 187)
      - K's, 1941 - 1982; 9 folders (Box 187, Box 188)
      - L's, 1941 - 1982; 11 folders (Box 189, Box 190)
      - M's, 1941 - 1982; 27 folders (Box 190, Box 191, Box 192)
      - N's, 1941 - 1982; 6 folders (Box 192, Box 193)
      - O's, 1941 - 1982; 3 folders (Box 193)
      - P's, 1941 - 1982; 13 folders (Box 193, Box 194)
      - Q's, 1941 - 1982 (Box 195)
      - R's, 1941 - 1982; 13 folders (Box 195, Box 196)
      - S's, 1941 - 1982; 23 folders (Box 196, Box 197, Box 198)
      - T's, 1941 - 1982; 5 folders (Box 198)
      - W's, 1941 - 1982; 16 folders (Box 199, Box 200)
      - U's - V's, 1941 - 1982 (Box 200)
      - V's, 1941 - 1982; 2 folders (Box 200)
      - Y's - Z's, 1941 - 1982 (Box 200)
      - Z's, 1941 - 1982 (Box 200)
    - Rejected Applicants, 1941 - 1982
      - A's, 1941 - 1982 (Box 201)
      - B's, 1941 - 1982 (Box 201)
      - C's, 1941 - 1982 (Box 201)
      - D's, 1941 - 1982 (Box 201)
      - E's, 1941 - 1982 (Box 201)
      - F's, 1941 - 1982 (Box 201)
      - G's, 1941 - 1982; 2 folders (Box 201)
      - H's, 1941 - 1982 (Box 201)
      - I's, 1941 - 1982 (Box 201)
      - K's, 1941 - 1982 (Box 202)
      - L's, 1941 - 1982 (Box 202)
      - M's, 1941 - 1982 (Box 202)
      - N's, 1941 - 1982 (Box 202)
      - P's, 1941 - 1982 (Box 202)
      - R's, 1941 - 1982 (Box 202)
      - S's, 1941 - 1982 (Box 202)
      - T's, 1941 - 1982 (Box 202)
      - V's, 1941 - 1982 (Box 202)
      - W's, 1941 - 1982 (Box 202)
      - Y's, 1941 - 1982 (Box 202)
      - Z's, 1941 - 1982 (Box 202)
- Financial Operations
  - Accounting Records, 1944 - 1972; Arranged chronologically. The letter size box contains accountant's reports (1951-1972). The oversize box contains larger reports (9" x 12") (1944-1950) from Ferro, Berdon and Company. Reports summarize revenues and expenditures for salaries, the Journal, membership, and conferences. For other financial records, SEE ALSO: Record Group 1 – Journal (Administrative subgroup - Advertising, Publishing and Printing series); Record Group 2 - Annual Meetings (Administrative Files subgroup, all folders titled "Bills"); and Record Group 6 - Budget and Tax Records subgroups.
    - Accountant's Reports (oversize), 1944 - 1950 (Box 210)
    - Accountant's Reports, 1951 (Box 203)
    - Accountant's Reports, 1952 (Box 203)
    - Accountant's Reports, 1953 (Box 203)
    - Accountant's Reports, 1954 (Box 203)
    - Accountant's Reports, 1955 (Box 203)
    - Accountant's Reports, 1956 (Box 203)
    - Accountant's Reports, 1957 (Box 203)
    - Accountant's Reports, 1958 (Box 203)
    - Accountant's Reports, 1959 (Box 203)
    - Accountant's Reports, 1960 (Box 203)
    - Accountant's Reports, 1961 (Box 203)
    - Accountant's Reports, 1962 (Box 203)
    - Accountant's Reports, 1963 (Box 203)
    - Accountant's Reports, 1964 (Box 203)
    - Accountant's Reports, 1965 (Box 203)
    - Accountant's Reports, 1966 (Box 203)
    - Accountant's Reports, 1967 (Box 203)
    - Accountant's Reports, 1968 (Box 203)
    - Accountant's Reports, 1969 (Box 203)
    - Accountant's Reports, 1970 (Box 203)
    - Accountant's Reports, 1969 (Box 203)
    - Accountant's Reports, 1971 (Box 203)
    - Accountant's Reports, 1970 (Box 203)
    - Accountant's Reports, 1972 (Box 203)
    - Accountant's Reports, 1971 (Box 203)
    - Accountant's Reports, 1973 (Box 203)
    - Accountant's Reports, 1972 (Box 203)
  - Budget, 1941 - 1948; Arranged chronologically. Contains administrative type correspondence with accountants Ferro, Berdon and Company (1944-1951), financial statements for the Journal, an "analysis of annual expenditures of the Journal and Society" (no date), Journal budget figures, and an agenda of a meeting of the Advisory Committee to discuss funds (ca. 1946).
    - Budget Allocation, 1944 - 1948; 2 folders (Box 204)
    - Correspondence with Accountants, 1941 - 1944 (Box 204)
  - Tax Records, 1951 - 1974; Tax records (1951-1974) include tax returns, filing instructions, and correspondence among officers, and between office staff and accountants.
    - Tax Records, 1951 - 1970; 4 folders (Box 204)
    - Tax Records, 1970 - 1974; 2 folders (Box 204)
- Printed Materials, Organized chronologically. This record group contains bulletins for the years 1943, 1944, 1946, 1950, and 1959 only, which discuss the Society's aims, membership guidelines and activities and sometimes list names of officers, Council members, and research committees and committee members. The "bulletin" series was discontinued between 1959 and 1967 and replaced by "brochures" containing similar information. The collection has brochures for the years 1967, 1971, 1980, and 1982 only. They give a history of the Society as well as a "scope and philosophy" note and provide a list of names and dates of the Society's presidents from 1943. Mailings and letterhead form the third portion of this record group. Found here are letterhead samples and a variety of blank printed forms used by the Society from 1939 to 1981 (e.g. monograph order forms, membership application forms, conference and forum announcements, ballots, hotel reservation forms).
  - Bulletins, 1943 - 1959
    - Bulletin, 1943 (Box 205)
    - Bulletin, 1944 (Box 205)
    - Bulletin, 1946 (Box 205)
    - Bulletin, 1950 (Box 205)
    - Bulletin, 1959 (Box 205)
  - Brochures, 1967 - 1982
    - Brochure, 1967 (Box 205)
    - Brochure, 1971 (Box 205)
    - Brochure, 1980 (Box 205)
    - Brochure, 1982 (Box 205)
  - Mailings and Letterhead, 1939 - 1975
    - Mailings and Letterhead, 1939 - 1946; 2 folders (Box 205)
    - Mailings and Letterhead, 1947 - 1951 (Box 205)
    - Mailings and Letterhead, 1952 - 1965; 3 folders (Box 205)
    - Mailings and Letterhead, 1966 - 1974 (Box 205)
    - Mailings and Letterhead, 1975 (Box 205)
- Administrative Files
  - Correspondence, 1943 - 1986; The first and second boxes ("Subjects") include correspondence regarding attendance by members at international conferences (1957-1961), funding foundations (1943-1945), organizations of which the Society was a member (e.g., National Society for Medical Research, World Federation of Mental Health), and revisions and drafts of the Society's bulletins. The third and fourth boxes comprise a "General Correspondence" series (1943-1967) organized alphabetically by name of individual, organization, or Journal title. It contains requests for information on a range of topics including membership, psychosomatic literature, and the Journal.
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science, Undated (Box 206)
    - Bulletin Revision, 1946 (Box 206)
    - Bulletin Revision, 1949 - 1950 (Box 206)
    - Bulletin Revision, 1952 - 1959; 2 folders (Box 206)
    - Bulletin Revision, 1967 (Box 206)
    - Brochure Revision, 1975 (Box 206)
    - Brochure Revision, 1979 - 1981 (Box 206)
    - Foundations, 1943 - 1945 (Box 206)
    - International Affairs, 1957 - 1961; 4 folders (Box 206)
    - National Society for Medical Research, 1959 - 1986; 2 folders (Box 207)
    - World Federation for Mental Health, 1949 - 1972; 6 folders (Box 207)
    - "General Correspondence" A-K, 1943 - 1967; 11 folders (Box 208)
    - "General Correspondence" L-Z, 1943 - 1967; 13 folders (Box 209)